{
    "id": "9f44d388a4f04828881175bd35ba74b2",
    "title": "Tenses Gap Filling Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "After he …………………………….. his exams, he went to Asia for a month.",
            "description": "Either the simple past or the past perfect can be used here. ",
            "answers": [
                "finished",
                "had finished",
                "finishes",
                "has finished"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I wish I ………………………….. curly hair.",
            "description": "A simple past is used after I wish to express regrets. ",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "has",
                "had"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Ten o’clock – it is time you ……………………………………… to bed.",
            "description": "A simple past is used after it is time to refer to the present or future. ",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "have gone",
                "went"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Don’t come and see me tomorrow. I would rather you …………………………… on Monday.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "come",
                "have come",
                "had come",
                "came"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "She ……………………………… jobless for six months.",
            "description": "A present perfect is used to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "has been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We ……………………………….. each other since Christmas.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "didn't see",
                "haven't seen",
                "hadn't seen"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "That is the third banana you ……………………………… this morning.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used in this structure. ",
            "answers": [
                "ate",
                "have eaten",
                "had eaten"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………………… two rooms since lunchtime.",
            "description": "The present perfect puts emphasis on the idea of completion. ",
            "answers": [
                "have painted",
                "have been painting",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………….. all afternoon.",
            "description": "The present perfect continuous puts emphasis on the idea of continuity. ",
            "answers": [
                "have painted",
                "have been painting",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I am sure we ………………………………….. before.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "met",
                "have met",
                "had met"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………….. ill last week.",
            "description": "Use the simple past to say when something happened. ",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He …………………………….. ill for more than a week.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "has been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}